A Guide to the Charlottesville, Virginia, 200th Anniversary Celebration Papers, 1909-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Charlottesville, Virginia, 200th Anniversary Celebration Papers 1909-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
38-92-b
This collection consists of ca. 200 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift to the Library frrom John G. Hundley of Charlottesville, Virginia, on May 18, 1983.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of ca. 200 items, 1909-1964, material relating to the Charlottesville 200th Anniversary Celebration in 1962. The anniversary program,, administered by the Charlottesville 200th Anniversary Commission, began in the Spring of 1962 and extended in to the Fall. Photographs. Two scrapbooks, and material regarding a historical pageant depicting the history of Charlottesville comprise the main body of this collection. Most of the photographs are of publicity announcements or of th historical pageant "Let Freedom Ring ". The movies are of portions of the pagaent as well as a fashion show, parade, pie eating, contest and concert. Two other photographs are also present-- one of J.G. Thurmond and another of Redlands Club, Charlottesville, Virginia. A telegram from President John F. Kennedy to the Charlottesville 200th Anniversary Celebration Commission, a script and cast list for "Let Freedom Ring," and commemorative coins and automobile license tags complete the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the following order: Telegram, scripts and cast list, photographs, printed material, memorabilia, and oversize items.
Contents List
- Telegram: John F. Kennedy to Charlottesville 200th Anniversary Celebration 1962 July 9, (2 items)
- Let Freedom Ring: Script and cast list [1962], (2 items)
- Photographs of bicentennial auto license tag 1962, (11 items)
- Photographs of Harold Burrows and Mrs. Kenneth Burrows 1962, (2 items)
- Photographs: Cavaliers and Belles in Richmond 1962, (4 items)
- Photographs of bicentennial concert (director, orchestra, singer) and pageant 1962, (64 items)
- Photographs of narrators of pageant 1962, (19 items)
- Photographs of pageant rehersal 1962, (8 items)
- Photographs of bicentennial Queen candidates 1962, (36 items)
- Photographs of University of Virginia Glee Club 1962, (12 items)
- Photographs of premiere of travel exhibit 1961 Aug 10, (14 items)
- Photographs of Monticello and Rotunda [1962], (8 items)
- Charlottesville: Photographs and postcards (44 items) 1905-1936, 1964
- Photographs of J.G. Thurmond n.d., (1 item)
- Photograph of law office at 0 Court Square n.d., (1 item)
- Miscellaneous photographs 1962, (20 items)
- Visiting Citizen Award 1962, (2 items)
- Printed material 1962, (13 items)
- Memorabilia 1962, (10 items)
- Scrapbook 1961 Jan.- 1962 May
- Scrapbook 1962 Jun- Sept
- Photographs: Monticello [1962], (2 items)
- Motion Picture Films
  - Charlottesville 200th Anniversary Celebration reel 1 Volkfest-- Building dedication, Pageant, Let Freedom Ring, Fashion Show, misc. And [out takes]: 1 14 inch reel, B & W, no sound, 16 mm. (F 280-A) 1962
  - Charlottesville 200th Anniversary Celebration, Reel 2 "Volkfest"-- Parade on West Main Street, picnic at McIntire Park, ect., misc. And [out takes]; 1 11 inch reel, B & W, no sound, 16 mm. (F 280-B) 1962